O'Brien, Leo W.; Papers apap267
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Leo W. O'Brien Papers
1939-1966
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
O'Brien, Leo W., 1900-1982
apap267
6.25 cubic ft.
The Leo W. O' Brien Papers document O'Brien's service in the House of Representative where he served from 1952-1966 on behalf of Albany, NY. The collection includes subject files, correspondence and various communications materials from his Congressional tenure.
Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted with the exception of select files noted below which contain individual constituent information of a sensitive nature. Researchers seeking access to these materials should contact the head of Special Collections and Archives.
Acquisition Information
Leo W. O'Brien donated his papers to Syracuse University in a series of acquisitions between 1966-1969. In 2006 the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
Leo W. O’Brien was born in Buffalo, Erie County, New York on September 21, 1900. He graduated from Niagara University in Niagara, New York in 1922. He pursued a career in journalism and worked for The International News Service, The Albany Knickerbocker Press, the Albany Times-Union and other newspapers. He was a newsman and radio and television commentator in Albany for 30 years.
A Democrat, O’Brien was elected in 1952 in a special election to fill Representative William T. Byrne’s seat after Byrne's death. O'Brien was subsequently elected for a full term and then returned to Congress for the next six terms, retiring in 1966. O'Brien first represented the 32nd Congressional District, and, after redistricting, the 30th and later the 29th.
O'Brien was a member of the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs and led the Statehood for Alaska and Hawaii movement. He sponsored legislation to create the Fire Island National Seashore and also supported plans to protect the Hudson River. O'Brien was later chair of the Albany County Planning Board and the Adirondack Study Commission.
O'Brien died at 81 years of age on May 4, 1982 and was survived by his wife, son, and eight grandchildren.
Scope and Contents
The Leo W. O’Brien Papers document his service in the U.S. Congress representing Albany, New York. The O’Brien Papers consist of subject files, the largest series, correspondence, and communications containing newspaper clippings and speeches. Researchers should note the many materials focusing on O’Brien’s interest in Alaska and Hawaii statehood and governance of U.S. territories, including Guam, Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands.
Please note that O'Brien's predecessor Representative William T. Byrne created the earliest materials in this collection from 1939 and the early 1940s. O'Brien retained select papers of Byrne's, filed them and later added his own materials on the same subjects to the files.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject Files, 1939-1966, Undated
Series 2 - Correspondence, 1940-1966, Undated
Series 3 - Communication, 1942-1966, Undated
All series are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Politics and Politicians; Law--United States--Territories and possessions; Statehood (American politics); Albany (N.Y.); New York (State)--Politics and government; Hawaii--Politics and government; Alaska--Politics and government; United States--Territories and possessions; Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legislative Records; Photographs; O'Brien, Leo W., 1900-1982.; Byrne, William Thomas, 1876-1952.; United States. Congress. House.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Subcommittee on Territories and Insular Possessions.; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Subcommittee on Pacific Affairs.; United States. Alaska International Rail and Highway Commission
- Subject Files, 1939-1966; Undated; 1; 4 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the general subject files of Representative O'Brien’s office including: amendments, bills, legislative records, news clippings, pamphlets, photographs, speeches, statements, and constituent correspondence.
  - Abele, Karpis HR-1301, 1954-1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Academy Appointments for Guam, V.I., etc. HR-84712,7805, 1957; 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Alabama County Council Civil Defense HR-4917, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Alaska International Rail and Highway Commission, 1957-1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Alaska International Rail and Highway Commission HR-319, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Alaska International Rail and Highway Commission extend HR- 3874, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Alaska Mental Health Act HR-6334, 4096, 1955-1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Alaska-Provide Hospitalization/Care of the Mentally Ill HR-6376, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Alaska-Statehood HR-7999,11664, 1956-1958 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Albany Air Reserve, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Albany County Airport, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Albany, Port of, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Albany-Urban Redesign, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - American Samoa-Deputy to Congress HR-5122, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - American Samoa-Extend Application of Certain Laws HR-10062, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Aniline HR-5896, 3608, 1953-1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16-17)
  - Aniline-Amend-Trading with the Enemy Act HR-3460, 1957; 1960-1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Antarctica HR-4297, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Antarctica-Study of Research HR-7486, 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Anti-Submarine Warfare Training and Mobilization Proposed Plan, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Area Redeveloped Administration HR-9446, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Armed Forces-Compensation WWII/Korean Conflict, 1959 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Arsenal, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Arsenal Watervliet, NY, 1955; 1957-1958; 1960-1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Aryeh, Gabriel and Sara HR-4474, 4989, 1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Authorized Reimbursement-Moving Expenses HR-4660, 12602, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - "B Company", 1954-1955 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Bartke, Kathe HR-1697, 1953-1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Bill Information-Miscellaneous, 1966; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Bollings Bill-Relief for Missionary of Our Lady of Mercy HR-10283, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Buy American Act-Ameno HR-6060, 1959-1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Byrne, 1950-1952 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Cannon HR-1206, 11968, 1955-1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Cavanagh, George B., 1939-1944; 1949-1950; 1953; 1956-1957 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Cemetery Commission HR-4475, 1742, 5, 1949-1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Certificate-National Press Club, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Cohoes, 1958; 1960-1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Cohoes Housing Authority, 1957-1958; 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Cohoes Post Office, 1951; 1961 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Communications Act of 1934-Amending HR-8779, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Communications Satellite System HR-10808, 1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Communist Party Outlawed HR-8363, 1954 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Constitution-Amendment HJR-174, 66 HR-12747, 1957-1962 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Correspondence-Miscellaneous, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Davis-Bacon Act-Amendment HR-10629, 1956 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Ebrahimian, Moosa, 1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Extend Authority Secretary of the Interior, through Geological Survey to Areas Outside National Domain-HR-4751, 1961 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Federal Construction Contract Act of 1955 HR-10628, 1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Fire Island National Seashore HR-6934, 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Foreign Service Study HJR-65, 301, 1957; 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Gasparri, Doctor Piero HR-5024, 1954-1955 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - General Aniline and Film Corp., 1961; 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Gitto, Epitania HR-8668, PR 86-383, 1949-1950; 1957-1959; 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Government Publications, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Great Lakes-Hudson River Waterway HR-8847, 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Great Lakes-Hudson River Waterway-Amend Public Law 409 HR-12136, 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Great White Fleet H. Con. Res. 330, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Guam HR-4215, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Guam HR-10630, 10631, 11041, 11042, 9609, 1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Guam-Amend to Sue Government HR-4603, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Guam, American Samoa, Trust Territory-Authorize Federal Assistance in Major Disasters HR-7642, 1961 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Guam, etc.-Assist in Major Disasters HR-11448, 1960 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Guam-Elective Governor and Lt. Governor HR-11379, 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Guam-Grant Certain Filled Lands Submerged Lands Tidelands HR-10997, 1960 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Guam-Governor, 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Guam-Navy to Acquire Land HR-3677, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Guam-Provide Popular Election of the Governor HR-12419, 1964 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Guam-Rehabilitation of HR-6225, 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Guam-Represented in the House HR-6791, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Guam-Resident Commissioner HR-8537, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Guam-Territorial Deputy HR-6023, 1960-1961; 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Guam, Virgin Islands-Amend Organic Act re: Appointment of Acting Sec. HR-10063, 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Guam, Virgin Islands-American Samoa Place Submerged Land within Jurisdiction of HR-4800, 1961 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Guam, Virgin Islands-Cadets and Midshipper-Appointment HR-7805, 1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Haischer, Francis M., 1958-1999 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Hakim, Abdullah Ibrahim HR-2337, 1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Hawaii, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Hawaii-Extend Judicial Distinct to include American Samoa, 1964 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Hawaii Omnibus Act HR-10456, 1960 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Hawaii-Provide Admission into the Union HR-4221, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Hawaii-Statehood-HR-848, 11663, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Hawaii-Statehood HR-888, 4221, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Hawaii-Statehood and Admission to Union, 1965; Undated (Flat-file 1)
  - Hawaii-Trip by Leo O' Brien, 1958-1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Hayes, Hon. John P. HR-613, 2229, 1945-1946; 1949-1951; 1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Hayes, John P. HR-613, 1951-1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Henry Hudson Celebration HJR-419, 290, 1953; 1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Hospital Facilities-Establishment of HR-3551, 9266, 1961; 1963 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Housing Act of 1950-To Amend Title IV Loans to Colleges for Science Bldg., etc. HR-401, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - HR Bills-Miscellaneous, HRes-592, HR- 3607, 8385, 8958, 4096, 1955-1956 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Hudson, 1945; 1948-1955; 1957-1958 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Hudson, 1959-1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Hudson-Champlain HJRes-484, 1958 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Hudson-Champlain, 1945; 1947-1951; 1954 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Hudson-Champlain-Commemorative Stamp HR-5815, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Hudson River Project HR-13508, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Hudson River Project, 1951-1955; 1957 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Hudson River Project, 1945; 1947-1951; 1954 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Immigration Material, 1962; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Import Restriction-Knit Hand Wear HR-3872, 1959 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Interior, 1957 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Interior Bill HR-8385, 1956 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Interior and Insular Affair, 1957-1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5-6)
  - Internal Revenue Code-Amendment Sec. 37 HR-3458, 1959; 1961 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Internal Revenue Code-Amendment HR-12087, 1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Internal Revenue Code of Amendment HR-6873, 6874, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - International Correspondence-Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Interstate Commerce Act Amendment HR-6681, 1961 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Interstate Commerce Act Amendment Repeal Sec. 13a HR-11651, 1962 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Interstate Route 89, 1962-1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Ira, Felix S. (Dr.) HR-1599, 1958-1960 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Isgro, Nunzio HJRes-617, 1954-1957 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Italy-Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Jensen, George Seeman HR-3861, 1949; 1954-1956 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Johnson, Mrs. Inge H. HR-7064, 1957 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Kelleher, Brigadier General, 1944; 1962 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Kii, Mieko HR-71142, 1954-1956 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Kothari, Dr. Nauttam J. HR-6231, 1952; 1958-1961 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Kwajalein and Dalap Islands-Compensation for Use and Occupancy of HR-11952, 1962 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Lead/Zinc Industry-Stabilize HR-6343, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Memorial Markers HR-1204, 1955; 1957 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Milk Publicity Bureau HR-8535, 1954 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Moraitis, Dimitrios HR-9797, 1957-1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - National Economic Conversion Commission HR-11181, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - National System of Interstate and Defense Highways Amend U.S. Code HR-3871, 1959 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings-Miscellaneous, 1954; 1965 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Newspaper Clippings-Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - New York State-Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Niagara Thruway, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - NY Canal System, 1948; 1951-1954; 1956 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - NYS Delegation Steering Committee, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34-35)
  - NY World's Fair Federal Participation in HR-743, 1960 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Olympic Games in U.S-Extending Invitation to the International Olympic Committee HJR-337, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Palmyra Island HR-8125, 1959 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Poskanzer, Israel Baird HR-7826, 1956-1958 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Prohibit the Use of Stopwatches or Other Devices in the Postal Service HR-4542, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Projects Rights of Blind to Self-Expression HR-3197, 1958-1959; 1961; 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Puerto Rico, 1958-1959 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Puerto Rico-Establish Commission etc. HR-5946, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Puerto Rico-Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Puerto Rico-Statehood, 1966 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Railroad Retirement Act of 1937-Amendement HR-850, 4353, 10627, 1956-1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Railroad Retirement Act of 1937-Amendement HR-3607, 1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Rapp, Dr. Marvin A., 1957-1958; 1960 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Rayburn Memorial in House HR-503, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Roosevelt Centennial Commission, 1954; 1956-1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Seftel, Lucienne J. (nee Gachoud) HR-8442, 1955-1956 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Senno, Jeannette S. Hr-3497, 1959-1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - "Severance Pay" HR-1205, 1956-1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Sister Giovina (Rosina Vitale) and Sister Olga (Calogera Zeffiro) HR-1304, 1954-1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Sister Saveria (Angela Lauria) HJRes-605, 1955-1956 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Social Security-Policeman and Firemen HR-7935, 1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Society of American Value Engineers, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Spring, Adelheid Walla HR-1302, 1953-1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - S.S. Coverage to State Employees HR-5836, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Statute of Limitations HR-529, 1950-1953 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Tax Exemption for VA Chaplains HR-3742, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Ten Percent Income Tax Forgiveness HR-12542, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Theodore Roosevelt-Establish Memorial in the National Capitol HR-8544, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Tires-Safety Standards HR-10773, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Trading with the Enemy Act HR-3460, 1959-1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Trading with the Enemy-Amendment HR-3608, 1955 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands HR-3198, 1963-1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands Provide Settlement of Claims HR- 12078, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands Remove Ceiling-Appropriations HR-9958, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Turkett, Agnes (Mrs.) HR-873, 1948; 1951-1953; 1956 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands Correspondence about HR-17505, 1966 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Uniformed Services-Equalize Pay of Retired Members HR-5129, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Uzar, Mrs. Vartanus HR-6082, 1960-1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Valente, Samuel, 1945-1947 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Valente, Samuel, 1946-1947 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Vassilatos, John HR-874, 1950-1954 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Vincent, William J. HR-3498, 1958-1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Vincentian Institute-Annual Visits, 1958-1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Virgin Islands HR-8297, 1957 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Virgin Islands HR-10254, 10255, 10256, 1955-1956 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Virgin Island-Clarify Ownership of Church Properties HR-11852, 1960 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Virgin Islands-General Obligation Bonds HR-11953, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Virgin Islands-Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Virgin Islands-Resident Commissioner HR-8535, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Virgin Islands-Revised Organic Act HR-5128, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Virgin Islands-Revised Organic Act Amendment HR-7666, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Virgin Islands-Revised Organic Act Amendment HR-7870, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Virgin Islands-Revised Organic Act Amendment HR-11954, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Virgin Islands Corporation Act HR-4750, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Virgin Islands-Virgin Islands Corporation HR-12211, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - War Claims Act of 1948, 1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - War Claims Act of 1948 HR-4753, 1959; 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - War Claims Act of 1948-Amendment HR-6938, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Washington D.C.-Miscellaneous, 1965-1966 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Western World Magazine, 1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Wilderness Society, 1958; 1962-1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - 86th-89th Congress-Bills Introduced, 1959-1965 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - 200th Anniversary of Congress of 1754 HJR-290, 1953-1954 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 53)
- Correspondence, 1940-1966; Undated; 2; 1 cubic ft.
  This series contains letters from and to Representative O’Brien (or Byrne). Please note the significant amount of correspondence related to service academy appointments. Many of these files are restricted.
  - Air Force Academy-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1954-1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
  - Air Force Academy-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1955-1956 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Air Force Academy-Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Air Force Academy '65-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1962-1965 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Air Force Academy-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1964-1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Air Force Academy-Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1949-1950 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1950-1952 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1952-1953 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1953-1954 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence- [RESTRICTED], 1956-1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1964-1965 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1964-1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Annapolis-Correspondence, 1966 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Bailey, Thomas-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1955-1956 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Breslin, Michael J.-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1957 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Burkhard, William E.-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1954-1956 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Carlotto, Munninger-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1940-1941 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Carroll, Arthur Thomas-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1954-1955 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Ceccucci, Randolph-Correspondence-[RESTRICTED], 1956-1957; 1960 (Box 5 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)